bav Das Gupta MD and CEO at IC Lomar to
discuss what this actually means for the
industry so let's go cross and listen
it yeah this is the third edition of the
uh the Risk Index that we launched uh I
think the good news is that if you look
at the Risk Index the Risk Index score
has gone up by one point that's a good
news but it's driven by two things one
the overall uh you the risk exposure has
gone up but the risk management score
has gone up even further so the I think
the KE message that we getting is that
corporate India is looking at risk much
in a much more focused Manner and trying
to manage risk better coming back to
your question about insurance look at
the end of the day if you look at all
the risk that corporates have everything
is not insurable you know in corporate
Risk Index we talk about business risk
external risk inflation risk these are
not things that we can control but there
are three or four of those parameters
that we can uh give protection for in
all of those areas there are new
emerging risks you know natural hazards
climate change cyber risk new
technologies that are emerging new
business models that are emerging in
terms of using some of those
Technologies to manufacture so all of
these things are changing and the role
for insurance will always be there to
cover these risks and so which segment
or which sector uh the role will improve
going ahead because the particular
sector need to focus more on risk
management what we've seen under is that
you know across sectors there is a range
and there are certain you know large
organizations seem to be doing a better
job of risk management uh and as as it
goes down down it you know as a size
becomes smaller the score is not as high
so clearly the smaller companies there
is clearly a scope of working with them
and Advising them on improving their
Risk Index if you look at within each of
those large medium and small there are
certain sectors where lot more work can
be done uh we see certain sectors like
mining
manufacturing uh you know some of the uh
retail side there is there is scope for
new age you know technology company
there's scope for doing a lot more work
I think the objective that we have at
ICS of preparing this index is to give a
tool to boards and corporates to
understand where they stand Visa their
sector and Vis Industries and we can
then help them in terms of whatever they
can do to improve their RIS scoree and
our senses there's enough scope for for
work there yes sir from 1 of April we
have seen that uh expenses of management
new regulation being implemented so how
beneficial it is for uh non-life
insurance company general insurance
company then particularly for your
insurance company also because you are
the biggest player in private space so
the eom regulation is a progressive
regulation uh if you look at uh you know
regulation across the world uh most
insurance companies are measured only on
solvency uh they don't even have an eom
regulation in India we had eom within
that we had subl limits for every
expense for every line of business so it
was very very honorous for insurance
companies in India to manage uh you know
all of those regulations